SAM OUIMFT

Projects

Customer Churn Prediction

Predicted customer churn with a Telco company's product and customer data using most modern classification algorithms. Built a comprehensive dashboard with Tableau to present the findings in a simplified yet interactive format.

Used an electronics company's sales data and Python to answer critical business questions, such as the best time to display an ad, which products are most often sold together and more.

Worked with the Johns Hopkins COVID-19 data source to build an interactive dashboard in Tableau that displays the growth of confirmed cases and deaths in worldwide geographic locations.

Movie Script NLP and Recommender

Performed NLP and topic modeling on web scraped, full-length movie scripts for the purpose of visualizing story arcs and recommending movies based on script similarity.

NFL Game Outcome Prediction

Web-scraped several years of NFL game, vegas odds, and team power ranking data to create a unique dataset for predicting individual game outcomes with various classification algorithms. Engineered exponential moving average features and 64 percent predictive accuracy was achieved.

Experience

Data Science Student

Jan. 2020 to Mar. 2020 New York, NY

Completed the only accredited (ACCET) data science bootcamp in the country, which focused on data analysis, machine learning, programming in multiple languages (Python, SQL, Bash), project design, and communication. During the course of the program, I completed 5 projects all of which heavily involved data analysis, either supervised or unsupervised algorithmic modeling, and an in-person presentation to peers.

Professional Development

Aug. 2019 to Jan. 2020

Followed various online educational programs and a self-made curriculum to sharpen my analytical toolset (Python, SQL, math). This involved completing such courses as Metis' 6-week online Python and Math for Data Science program, Coursera's Math for Data Science course taught by current Duke University Instructors, among many hours of additional self-learning.

CoinDesk

Markets Editor. Analyst (March 2019 - June 2019)

May 2018 to June 2019 New York. New York

- Lead the CoinDesk Markets initiative with two colleagues under my supervision.
- Accountable for scheduling, editing and publishing CoinDesk's markets written content.
- Authored over 100 articles featuring my technical analysis in addition to covering notable moves or events in the cryptocurrency markets; achieved over 2.5 million page views as of June 2019.
- Core creator and distributor of market and technical analysis via social media; grew the CoinDesk Markets following over 300 percent in one year (30k followers as of June '19).
- Contributed to and edited the CoinDesk Markets daily newsletter sent to 15-25k subscribers.
- Participated in senior meetings to assist in refining CoinDesk's editorial strategy and conducted interviews for future interns and the Markets Editor position.

Markets Analyst (October 2018 - March 2019)

- Responsible for authoring market analysis and news stories incorporating the use of Excel, Datawrapper and Trading View charts and graphs for CoinDesk's growing audience.
- Leading role in a paid partnership with Stocktwits, the premier social media platform for investors, as its first cryptocurrency media partner.
- Featured in CoinDesk's podcasts and Twitch streams to share my view on the cryptocurrency markets.

Markets Analyst Intern (May 2018 - October 2018)

- Authored crypto-market centric educational material including "how-to guides" on reading candlesticks, the relative strength index. MACD and more.
- Wrote price-related news stories and provided daily technical analysis using statistical trading methodologies on a variety of digital assets for CoinDesk's growing markets audience.

FanDuel

Oct. 2017 to Mar. 2018 New York, NY

- Customer Support, Payment Specialist (6-month contract) Provided support to all FanDuel users via ZenDesk, a high volume ticketing system, live chat and phone.
 - Specialized in user payment solutions using processors such as PayPal Business, Braintree and Apple Pay. Assisted users with Know Your Customer (KYC) Verification and identified fraud situations.

Certifications

Tableau Desktop Specialist

Certified by Tableau

Certified Bitcoin Professional

Certified by the Cryptocurrency Certification Consortium (C4) in February 2018

Contact

- samouimet@gmail.com
- samouimet.com
- **(201)** 572-5865
- **♥** Branchburg, NJ
- **y** samadamsSA0
- in samouimet1
- C) samad4ms

Skills

LANGUAGES AND LIBRARIES

Python IN2

Pandas Scikit-learn

NumPv

Beautiful Soup

NLTK

MACHINE LEARNING

Regression

Classification

NIP Clustering

VISUALIZATION

Tableau

Matplotlib

Plotly

Seaborn

DataWrapper

GENERAL

Business Acumen

Microsoft Office

Technical Analysis

Cryptocurrency

Writing

Wordpress

Education

Roger Williams University

B.S. Business Management 2017 Minor Electronic Business